3 ½ Minutes, 10 Bullets is a documentary, thriller, tv
movie film directed by Marc Silver.
Black Friday, the day after Thanksgiving November 2012, four boys in a red SUV pull into a gas
station after spending time at the mall buying sneakers and talking to girls.
With music blaring, one boy exits the car and enters the
store, a quick stop for a soda and a pack of gum.
A man and a woman pull up next to the boys in the
station, making a stop for a bottle of wine.
The woman enters the store and an argument breaks out when the driver
of the second car asks the boys to turn the music down.
3½ minutes and ten bullets later, one of the boys is dead.
3½ MINUTES dissects the aftermath of this fatal encounter.
Self, Jordan Davis' mother, played by Lucia McBath.
Self, Jordan Davis' father, played by Ron Davis.
Self, played by Michael David Dunn.
Self, Circuit Court Judge, played by Russell Healey.
Self, Asst. State Attorney, played by John Guy.
Self, Defense Attorney, played by Cory Strolla.
3 1/2 Minutes, 10 Bullets, also known as 3 1/2 Minutes, is a 2015
American documentary film written and directed by Marc Silver.
The film is based on the events surrounding the 2012 murder of Jordan Russell Davis and examines the shooting
itself, as well as the subsequent trial, media coverage and protests that resulted from the shooting.
The film premiered under its original title 3 1/2 Minutes at the Sundance Film Festival on
January 24, 2015, later winning the Special Jury Prize for Social Impact.
The film was then bought by HBO Documentary Films, and
premiered on HBO on November 23, 2015.
On December 1, it was one of 15 films shortlisted for the Academy Award for
Best Documentary Feature for the 2016 89th Academy Awards.
The tone is intense.